[
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the launch date of FFI in India?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "2023",
      "2023",
      "2023",
      "2023"
    ],
    "correctOption": "2023",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Who was announced as the brand Ambassador of FFI\ton its release meet?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Tendulkar",
      "SRK",
      "M.S.Dhoni",
      "Chhet"
    ],
    "correctOption": "M.S.Dhoni",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": " Which city is the host of the ODI Cricket World Cup 2023\u2019?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Chennai",
      "Mumbai",
      "Ahmedabad",
      "Kolkata"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Ahmedabad",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Researchers from which country have developed a new tool called the Data Carbon Ladder?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "India",
      "Brazil",
      "UK",
      "USA"
    ],
    "correctOption": "UK",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which country is organising the UNSC's first ever meeting on threats of Artificial Intelligence?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "India",
      "Australia",
      "UK",
      "Germany"
    ],
    "correctOption": "UK",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which country\u2019s king recently apologised for his country\u2019s role in slavery and asked for forgiveness during a historic speech?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "UK",
      "The Netherlands",
      "Spain",
      "Thailand"
    ],
    "correctOption": "The Netherlands",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Jens Stoltenberg has been elected as the head of which grouping for third time in a row?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "ASEAN",
      "BIMSTE",
      "NATO",
      "G-7"
    ],
    "correctOption": "NATO",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Who was the first person space?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Yuri Gargrin",
      "Neil Amstrong",
      "Edward Aldrin",
      "Donald Albert"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Yuri Gargrin",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "When did Chandryaan launch?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "14th July",
      "15th July",
      "11th July",
      "12th July"
    ],
    "correctOption": "14th July",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which airline was the first to lower their prices to accommodate poor people?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Spice Jets",
      "Air India",
      "Indigo",
      "Deccan Airlines"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Deccan Airlines",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Who did praggnandha play against in the chess world cup?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Vishwanathan Anand",
      "Magnus Carlsen",
      "Fabiano Caruana",
      "Gukesh"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Magnus Carlsen",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Who won the Fifa 2023 World Cup?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Argentina",
      "Brazil",
      "France",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Argentina",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Who won the US Open title of 2023?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Novak Djokovick",
      "Rafael Nadal",
      "Andy Murray",
      "Roger Federor"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Novak Djokovick",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Who wrote the one piece manga?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Kishimoto",
      "Oda",
      "Hajime Isayama",
      "Gege akimane"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Oda",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "What was the G20 Organizing working on during the recent summit?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Women empowerment",
      "Global economy",
      "Global security",
      "Climate Change"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Women empowerment",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which country/unions joined in G20 Organization?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Austria",
      "Germany",
      "African union",
      "Ottoman Union"
    ],
    "correctOption": "African union",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": " As Disney is going to celebrate their 100th anniversary this year, which month was it found?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "August",
      "December",
      "October",
      "November"
    ],
    "correctOption": "October",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which country has launched the \u2018Young Professional Scheme\u2019 for visas to Indians aged between 18 and 30?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "USA",
      "UK-",
      "Australia",
      "Canada"
    ],
    "correctOption": "UK-",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "For what purpose was Matsya 6000 built?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Deep sea research  ",
      "Fisher mam's loan  ",
      "Lunar research  ",
      "Ship building"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Deep sea research  ",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "India is collaborating with which country to frame a \u2018Consensus Document\u2019 for G-20?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "China",
      "Japan",
      "South Africa",
      "Bangladesh"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Japan",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which country has officially re-entered the UNESCO?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "India",
      "Russia",
      "USA",
      "Ukraine"
    ],
    "correctOption": "USA",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which Union Ministry has launched the \u2018Company Law Committee (CLC)\u2019?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Ministry of Corporate Affairs",
      "Ministry of Finance",
      "Ministry of MSME",
      "Ministry of Justice"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Ministry of Corporate Affairs",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "In how many years once the green comet appears in Earth?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "350 yrs",
      "500 yrs",
      "700 yrs",
      "400 yrs"
    ],
    "correctOption": "400 yrs",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which company made the infamous Titanic Submarine?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Sea Gate",
      "Marine Gate",
      "Ocean Gate",
      "DeepWater Gate"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Ocean Gate",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "How many Years has it been since the Guiness Record of books been made?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "67",
      "69",
      "70",
      "71"
    ],
    "correctOption": "70",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which of the Following countries are going to join the BRICS?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Portugal",
      "Canada",
      "Saudi Arabia",
      "Argentina"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Argentina",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which country has been the victim of the biggest economic downfall of 2023?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "India",
      "Uk",
      "US",
      "Australia"
    ],
    "correctOption": "US",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the world's first wind powered cargo ship was made by which 2 countries?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "US and UK",
      "UK and Germany",
      "Germany and US",
      "New Zeland and UK"
    ],
    "correctOption": "UK and Germany",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which social media platform faced controversy over user data privacy in recent years?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Twitter ",
      "Instagram ",
      "Facebook ",
      "LinkedIn"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Facebook ",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which company developed and launched the first mRNA-based COVID-19 vaccine?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Pfizer-BioNTech ",
      "Moderna ",
      "AstraZeneca ",
      "Johnson & Johnson"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Pfizer-BioNTech ",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which spacecraft successfully landed on Mars in 2021 to search for signs of past microbial life?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Voyager ",
      "Hubble Space Telescope ",
      "Perseverance ",
      "Rosetta"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Perseverance ",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the name of the space agency responsible for the Artemis program aiming to return humans to the Moon?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "ESA (European Space Agency)",
      "CNSA (China National Space Administration)",
      "NASA (National Aeronautics and Space Administration)",
      "ISRO (Indian Space Research Organisation)"
    ],
    "correctOption": "NASA (National Aeronautics and Space Administration)",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "In which year did SpaceX's Crew Dragon successfully send astronauts to the International Space Station (ISS)? ",
    "quizOptions": [
      "2018",
      "2019 ",
      "2020 ",
      "2021"
    ],
    "correctOption": "2021",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which social media platform introduced \"Fleets,\" a feature similar to Stories, which disappear after 24 hours? ",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Twitter",
      "Instagram ",
      "Snapchat ",
      "Facebook "
    ],
    "correctOption": "Twitter",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which country in the Middle East is known as the \"Land of the Pharaohs\" and is famous for its ancient history and monuments? ",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Jordan",
      "Lebanon ",
      "Egypt ",
      "Iraq "
    ],
    "correctOption": "Egypt ",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "What international agreement, signed in 2015, aimed to limit Iran's nuclear activities in exchange for sanctions relief?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "SALT II Treaty ",
      "INF Treaty ",
      "JCPOA (Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action) ",
      "START Treaty"
    ],
    "correctOption": "JCPOA (Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action) ",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "In 2022, which country hosted the FIFA World Cup, becoming the first Middle Eastern nation to do so? ",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Brazil ",
      "Qatar ",
      "Germany ",
      "Russia "
    ],
    "correctOption": "Qatar ",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Who won the Nobel Peace Prize in 2021 for her efforts to combat sexual violence as a weapon of war? ",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Malala Yousafzai ",
      "Greta Thunberg ",
      "Nadia Murad and Dr. Denis Mukwege ",
      "Kailash Satyarthi "
    ],
    "correctOption": "Nadia Murad and Dr. Denis Mukwege ",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "In 2021, which European country held a referendum to vote on a new constitution, making it the first nation to include climate protection in its constitution? ",
    "quizOptions": [
      "France",
      "Germany ",
      "Sweden ",
      "Italy"
    ],
    "correctOption": "France",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "In 2021, which cryptocurrency became legal tender in El Salvador, making it the first country to do so? ",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Bitcoin ",
      "Ethereum ",
      "",
      "Litecoin "
    ],
    "correctOption": "Bitcoin ",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "What international climate conference, scheduled for 2021, was postponed to 2022 due to the COVID-19 pandemic? ",
    "quizOptions": [
      "COP25 ",
      "COP26 ",
      "COP27 ",
      "COP28 "
    ],
    "correctOption": "COP26 ",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "Which Asian country faced widespread pro-democracy protests in 2021, leading to a military coup and subsequent political turmoil? ",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Thailand",
      "",
      "Vietnam ",
      "Cambodia "
    ],
    "correctOption": "",
    "explanation": ""
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "Current Affairs",
    "quizQuestion": "In 2021, the United States rejoined which international agreement aimed at addressing climate change, from which it had previously withdrawn? ",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Kyoto Protocol",
      "Montreal Protocol ",
      "Paris Agreement ",
      "Copenhagen "
    ],
    "correctOption": "Paris Agreement ",
    "explanation": ""
  }
]